我以为我可以放逐他
I thought I could let him go.
随着时间过去
Over time.
随着火车前进
With miles traveled.
我以为我可以剥掉威尔福德
I thought I could strip Wilford away.
让他的统治一点点被瓦解
Shed his rules one by one.
最终
And finally...
揭开他的面具
his mask.
直到他只是一个墙上的图标
Until he was just a logo on the wall.
你就是莱顿跟我们说的那人吧
You're the one Layton told us about, aren't you?
梅兰妮·卡维尔
Melanie Cavill.
你叫什么
What's your name?
她管理这里时可从来不
Don't remember her caring about our names
在乎我们叫什么
when she ran the place.
是啊
No, sir.
我印象里也是
Neither do I.
擦擦你的头吧
For your head.
你不用原谅我
You don't have to forgive me.
拿着吧
Just take it.
我能问你个问题吗
Can I ask you something?
前车真有大海吗
Is it true there's an ocean uptrain?
可美了
It's beautiful.
我以为我能看到
I thought I'd get to see it, you know?
我以为我能创造更善良温柔的世界
I thought I could create a kinder, gentler world.
做点什么
Do something.
别碰他
Hey, don't touch him!
但列车却另有想法
But the train demanded otherwise.
列车要血
The train demanded blood.
-不不 -造纸工人沃特·弗莱明
- No. No. No. - Walter "The Papermaker" Flemming,
你被判犯下叛车罪
you have been found guilty of treason
因此被判冰肺死刑
and are hereby sentenced to death by Lung of Ice.
不
Aah, no!
我喂它食物
I fed her.
现在轮到他们了
And now they will.
直到我们到达终点
Until we reach our final destination.
每个人都生活在同样的痛苦和怀疑里
Everyone the same in pain and doubt.
紧紧抱着我们的所失
Holding our losses close...
在雪国列车上
on Snowpiercer.
1001节车厢
1,001 cars long.
雪国列车
第一季 第九集
把气罐都收集到这里来
Collect all the gas canisters right here.
防线怎么样了
How are the lines holding?
叛乱那边没动静 长官
All quiet on the rebel front, sir.
他们逃了 准备推进
They're on their heels. Be ready to push.
是 长官
Yes, sir.
我们的支持者说
Our supporters tell us
守卫在前车集结
the Jackboots are stacking up at the front.
整支军队都在集结
The whole army's gathering.
嗯 我们该马上行动 抢先于他们
Yeah, we should move now, beat them to the punch.
不 我们得加固堡垒 保住我们的阵地
No. We need to reinforce the barricades, keep what we hold.
37人确认死亡
37 confirmed dead.
天知道前车还死了多少
God knows how many more uptrain.
-温妮 -我找不到我哥哥
- Winnie? - I can't find my brother.
我到处找了
I looked everywhere.
他...
He's, uh...
他死了 亲爱的
He's gone, honey.
他跟你妈妈在一起了
He's with your mother.
跟我来 亲爱的
Come with me, sweetheart.
安德烈
Andre?
怎么耽搁了 指挥官 我们为什么不前进
What's the holdup, Commander? Why aren't we advancing?
我们的计划正在进行
Our plan is on track.
打算一区一区的来
We go section by section.
德拉托雷先生进入永动机 并更改门的权限
Mr. De la Torre will access the engine and override the doors,
封锁区域 然后我们就放毒气
seal an area, and we'll flood it with gas.
之后我的人会进去清扫
Then my men enter and mop up.
如果毒气进入通风系统
If the gas gets in the ventilation system,
整趟列车都会有
it could spread train-wide.
你怎么确保不毒死平民
How do you avoid gassing civilians?
我们没打算
We won't.
-天呐 -老天爷
- Oh, dear God. - Jesus Christ.
如果他们保护叛乱分子 我们就别无选择
If they're sheltering rebels, they leave us no choice.
我们需要劳动力 不然我们没法生活
We need a workforce. Our lives depend on it.
我们会训练更多劳动力
We'll train more.
反正人口已经超标了
We're overpopulated as it is.
我们该讨论梅兰妮·卡维尔的处决
We should discuss Melanie Cavill's execution.
应该公开废黜
It should be a public dethroning.
你不能废黜海盗 而是让他们走跳板
You don't dethrone pirates. You make them walk the plank.
问题在于有秩序的权力交接
The point is that there are guidelines
有清楚的行动指南
for an orderly hand-over of power.
听听你们说的话 车尾人都暴动到门前了
Listen to you people. The Tailie horde is at the gate.
毁灭他们
Stamp them out.
现在就碾碎所有暴动的星星之火
Crush every last spark of this mutiny now forever,
否则就没有可交接的列车了
or there will be no train to hand over.
看那个 看那个
Look at that. Look at that.
你直接让她进来了 难以置信
You let her right in. Unbelievable.
你个小瘪三
You little shit!
-你知道自己干了什么吗 -我解放了车尾
- Do you have any idea what you've done? - I freed the Tail.
你又不是士兵 迈尔斯
You're not a soldier, Miles.
你只是个可怜孩子
You're a tragic child.
而这个 这是你理解不了的麻烦
And this? This is trouble you can't even fathom.
你知道吗
You know what?
你 小朋友 就坐在这里
You, my friend, you're gonna sit here.
安安静静的 一动也别动
You're gonna be quiet, and you're not gonna move.
如果你敢碰什么 我就把你碎尸万段
And if you touch anything, I will cut you into little pieces
扔进肥料厕所里
and put you in the composting toilet.
你明白吗
Do you understand?
Do you understand?!
给点力
Oh, come on.
那是无线电吗
Is that a radio?
闭嘴
Shut up!
给点力
Come on.
对我好点
Be good to me.
这是通讯备用设备
It's a comms backup.
短波信号
Short-range signal.
能到达车尾
Goes tip to tail.
为什么不用有线
Why not use the hard lines?
因为他们会监听 小子
'Cause they'll be listening in, kid.
如果梅兰妮在 她会知道怎么样
If Melanie's out there, she'll know to use this.
圣地亚哥 圣地亚哥
Santiago. Santiago.
我孙子 圣地亚哥
My grandson, Santiago.
你见过他吗 没有吗
Have you seen him? No?
-莱顿 真高兴见到你 -奶奶
- Layton. Nice to see. - Mama Grande!
我孙子圣地亚哥没回来
My grandson, Santiago, did not come back.
你在打斗时见到他了吗
Did you see him in the battle?
是的 他在前面的夜车
Yes. Yes. He was in the Nightcar on the front.
他还活着 朋友
He's alive still, amigo.
我能感觉到
I feel it.
莱顿
Layton?
-派克 -莱顿 好兄弟
- Pike. - Layton! My man!
老兄
Oh, dude.
见到你真好 兄弟
Good to see you, brother.
你看起来不错
You look good.
-你回来了 -嗯
- You're back. - Yeah.
大力士和终极破坏者呢
Where's Strong Boy and Z-Wreck?
我们能换个地方说吗
Can we talk somewhere?
事情很快就恶化了
Things went to shit pretty fast, didn't they?
现在头等厢又换了一批疯子管理
You know, there's a whole new group of lunatics running First.
福爵一家 还有那个特种部队男
You got the Folgers and then that -- that GI Joe guy.
而梅兰妮 今天就要被处决了
And Melanie -- Melanie's in line to be executed today.
很好
Good.
你见过前车的食物吗
Have you seen the food up there?
莱顿 他们有蛋糕 用的是橄榄油
Layton, they got this cake. And they use olive oil.
口感简直...
And the -- the -- the mouth feel is --
你为什么来这 派克
Why are you here, Pike?
因为我为你骄傲 兄弟
Because I am proud of you, brother.
你差点就完成了这一壮举
I mean, you damn near pulled this whole thing off.
那你也拿起长矛加入进来
Then grab a spear.
不 他们打算实行焦土政策
No, they're -- they're going scorched-earth.
一节车厢一节车厢地来
Car by car.
起义者 平民 你们都会被毒死
Rebels, civilians, they'll gas the lot of you.
不可能
They can't.
不可能 他们不可能这么做
No, they can't. They can't do it.
他们需要人来运行列车
They -- They need people to run the train.
你想验证下吗 他们正摩拳擦掌呢
You want to test that theory? 'Cause they're sure keen to.
放下武器 他们会放过你们的
Lay down your weapons. They'll show mercy.
你真信吗
You really believe that?
车尾人会回到车尾
The Tailies will go back to the Tail.
三等厢的人也会回到自己的岗位
The Thirdies will go back to work.
你能得到什么
What do you get?
干净的床单
Clean sheets.
新鲜的食物
F-Fresh food.
以及收拾你的烂摊子的快感
And the pleasure of mopping up your mess,
因为在你宣布投降后 你将被处死
because after you announce your surrender, you'll be executed.
你有一小时做决定 莱顿
You got one hour to decide, Layton.
用你一命换众生
Your life for all of theirs.
如果你真是你声称的那样 就接受这个条件
If you're half the man you claim to be, you'll take that deal.
就算你死了 这事也不会完
It's not gonna end with you.
我们也是
Or with us.
被毒死还是投降
Gas or surrender.
我们冒着失去一切奋斗成果的风险
We risk losing everything we fought for.
所以绝不投降
So there's no surrender.
行
Okay.
你得去和扎拉聊聊
You need to speak to Zarah.
这可能是最后的机会了
This may be your last chance.
去见她
Go see her.
拜托了
Please.
没有办法打开火车头门
So there's no way to open this engine door.
班尼特会竭尽全力守住车门
Bennett will hold out as long as he can.
他对梅兰妮很忠诚
He's loyal to Melanie.
你要得到那些系统的控制权 德拉托雷先生
You need to get control of those systems, Mr. De la Torre.
听着 也许莱顿会投降
Look, maybe Layton will surrender.
我们就不用放毒气了
Maybe we won't have to use the gas at all.
也许我会把他们杀个片甲不留
And maybe I'll slaughter every last one of them.
你能处理好这事吗
You can handle this position?
我去列车后方 覆盖主控制装置
I'll tap in downtrain, override the master controls.
他们几小时前就该到了
They should have been here hours ago.
我却和一群残废被困在这
And I'm stuck here with a bunch of invalids!
我们永远都无法战斗
We'll never be able to fight!
我想他明白的
I think he understands.
他好像能理解我们说的话
I think he can perceive what's being said.
你的大脑也许坏掉了
Your brain might be buggered,
但你体内的战士还在 对吧大力士
but the warrior's still there, aren't ya, Strong Boy?
终极破坏者
Z-Wreck?
你还好吗 能战斗吗
You ready to fight?
好得不能再好了
Never better.
那就这么定了
Well, that settles it, then.
我们走
Let's go.
克利姆特先生
And, Mr. Klimpt...
我们需要借用你的裤子 朋友
we're gonna need your trousers, my friend.
开什么玩笑
Bloody joking!
露丝
Ruthie.
你看这些 诺兰
Look at this, Nolan.
是音频文件
Audio files.
都是威尔福德先生以前的演讲和广播
Old speeches and broadcasts, all by Mr. Wilford.
她就是用这些录音来宣布公告的
That's how she did the announcements.
瞧 她有他的使用手册
Look, she's got his -- his manuals,
日记 工具
his journals, his tools.
声称她从他手下救了我们
Claims that she saved us from the man,
然而一直以来她都在这研究他的遗留物
while all this time she's been up here stewing in his juices.
她就是痴迷于他 痴迷了
Obsessed with him is what she is -- obsessed.
她死了没有 诺兰
Is she dead yet, Nolan?
我要亲手处死她
'Cause I'll ice her me bloody self.
你觉得我失去理智了 对吗
What, you think I've lost the plot, don't you?
恰恰相反
Quite the opposite.
你对这辆列车了如指掌
You know the soul of this Train.
我有军队
I have the army.
这两者是强有力的组合
That's a potent combination.
那福爵一家呢
Well, what about the Folgers?
在危机中尚有用处 他们在头等厢有影响力
Useful in a crisis. They have influence in First.
但恢复秩序后 自然力量便会发挥作用
But once order is restored, natural power exerts itself.
你和我 露丝
You and me, Ruthie.
我叫圣地亚哥
My name is Santiago.
到你了 卡维尔夫人
You're up, Ms. Cavill.
我会为你祈祷
I will pray for you.
上帝保佑
God bless!
克利福德
Clifford.
深吸一口气 这样能结束得更快
Just one big inhale. It goes faster that way.
求求你
Please.
梅兰妮·卡维尔 乘客服务部
Melanie Cavill, Hospitality Department,
你被判犯下叛车罪
you've been found guilty of treason
现判处你冰肺死刑
and are hereby sentenced to death by Lung of Ice.
梅 梅 梅
Mel, hey. Mel. Mel, Mel, hey.
梅 是我
Mel. Hey. It's me.
你没事吧
You alright?
哈维
Javi?
我们得把你救出去
We have to get you out of here.
坐下
Sit down!
别反抗了 起来
Quit resisting and get up!
这女人不在我的名单上
This woman's not on my list.
不确定她的身份 我没法继续
I can't continue without ID'ing her.
得去档案室 解决这问题
We'll have to go to Archives and get this sorted.
放开她
Put her down.
我们走 快走
Let's go. Let's go.
快点
Hurry.
祝你好运 梅
Good luck, Mel.
天啊 我浑身发抖
Oh, my God. I'm shaking.
你是怎么做到的
How did you do that?
胁迫和礼物 你以为是什么
Coercion and gifts. How do you think?
但我们没时间了 走吧 梅
But we don't have time. Come on, Mel.
我们得走了
We have to go.
梅
Mel.
前车还是有理智的人的
There are still reasonable people uptrain.
我们可以召集帮手 正面刚福爵家族
We can rally support, take the Folgers head-on.
头等厢沦陷了
First is lost.
整个列车都沦陷了
The entire train is lost.
但我们得试试
But we have to try.
待在前车
Stay uptrain.
小心点
Be careful.
-你要去哪 -后车
- Where are you going? - Downtrain.
梅 梅
Mel! Mel!
战斗结束了吗
Is the fighting over?
没有
No.
现在会发生什么
What's gonna happen now?
你是说我们的策略吗
You mean our strategy?
这个我就不告诉你了
Think I'll keep you out of that one.
我没指望你会原谅我
I don't expect you to forgive me.
好
Good.
那我们的想法一致
Then we on the same page.
乔茜身上发生的事
What happened to Josie,
我的余生都要扛着这份罪恶
I'll have to bear that weight for the rest of my life.
我做了我必须要做的
I did what I had to do...
保护我们的孩子
...to protect our child.
我得走了
I have to go.
好了 我们走吧
Alright, let's get moving.
结束了 提尔
It's over, Till.
什么叫结束了
What do you mean it's over?
不不不 没有结束
No, no, no, no. No, no, no. It's not over.
他们会杀了所有人
They will kill everyone.
他们会毁了全世界
They will take the whole goddamn world down.
你不能就这么放弃
No, you can't just give up.
人们相信了你 我也相信了你
People believed in you. I believed in you.
什么变了 莱顿
What changed, Layton?
看起来你心中已经有了答案
You look like a man with an answer.
告诉他们我同意了
Tell them yes.
我投降
I surrender.
他接受了交易
He took the deal.
你拿到他的项上人头 放他的人民一条生路
You get his head, and his people get mercy.
谢天谢地
Thank goodness.
我们能确定这不是在耍我们吗
Can we be sure it isn't a trick?
我已经告诉你了
I told you already that Layton
莱顿可不喜欢杀戮
does not have the stomach for bloodshed.
如果他有什么小心思的话 毒气已经就位了
Well, if he tries anything, the gas is in place.
那就这样 注意时间
Well, that settles it. Note the time.
第一场雪国列车战役在16小时内就结束了
The first Snowpiercer war is over in under 16 hours.
我会通知头等厢和二等厢现在的情况
I'll tell First and Second what's happened.
好 我来安排受降
Good. I'll arrange the surrender.
受降的时候你们应该在场
Y-You -- You guys should be there at the surrender.
威尔福德不在了
You know, Wilford's gone,
人们希望能有新的掌权人出现
and people are looking for the new face of power.
这会是历史性的时刻
It will be a historic moment.
如果你们不去的话
Yeah, for Commander Grey.
会变成格雷指挥官和露丝的时刻
And for Ruth, if you guys don't go.
全世界最狡猾的两个人
The two most cunning minds left on Earth,
都生活在我的车厢里
and you both live in my car.
我能问你一件事吗
Can I ask you something?
好
Yeah.
你为什么要让车尾一直又冷又黑的
Why did you keep it so cold and dark in the Tail?
这很复杂
It's complicated.
但是永动机拥有无限的能量输出
But the Engine Eternal has unlimited output.
无限是指时间 而不是强度
In duration, not in density.
这个恢复工作了
That is working.
在任一时间点 只有那么多的能量可用
At any given time, there's only so much to go around.
所以并不是那么复杂
So it's not that complicated.
富人和穷人的区别
Haves and have-nots.
听着 燃料可能是无限的
Listen, the fuel might be eternal,
但这些零件 这些东西不是
but these parts, these things are not.
总有一天
And someday,
我们所有人都会因为缺乏一个六角螺母而亡
the whole lot of us will die for want of a hex nut.
这是引擎室 请说 请说
This is the engine. Come in. Come in.
这是引擎室 再重复一遍 请说 请说
This is the engine. I repeat, come in. Come in.
是梅兰妮吗
Is it Melanie?
不是
No.
不是梅兰妮 只是干扰信号
It's not Melanie. It's just interference.
好的 下来
Alright, come on.
等一下
Hold.
你们 所有小队去车头
You! All units to the front!
下来吧 小伙子们
Come on, boys.
走吧
Let's go.
等等 等等
Wait, wait.
先听我说
Hear me out.
我应该就地杀了你
I should kill you right here!
我可以让你们得到列车
I can get you the train.
我知道如何能打败格雷的部队
I know how to defeat Grey's army.
你为什么要这样做
Why would you do that?
因为一旦他和福爵一家接管了
Because Snowpiercer won't survive
雪国列车就无法运转下去
with him and the Folgers in charge.
但我无法一个人做 我们必须迅速行动
But I can't do it on my own, and we have to act fast.
所有的守卫都聚集在一起了
All the Jackboots are gathered together.
如果我们断开列车的一节车厢
If we disconnect a section of the train,
我们就能一次性将他们击败
we can wipe them out in one go.
这要怎么做
How does that work?
班尼特将在引擎室统一指挥
Bennett will orchestrate from the engine,
但是我们需要在分离点
but we need to release manual safeties
打开手动安全阀
from the separation points.
前面的轨道会有一个叉道
There's a fork in the track ahead.
班尼特将会调节车速
Bennett will adjust speed
这样我们就能在精确的时间点行动
so that we hit it at the precise time,
释放列车 并把守卫部队送入冰冻世界中
releasing the cars and sending the Jackboot army into the freeze.
如果你所说的事可能做到的话
If what you're saying is even possible,
我们就相当于是帮你重获权力
we'd be clearing your way back to power.
我不会掌管
I won't be in charge.
你们会
You will.
所以你准备放弃掌管权
So, you're just gonna give up control.
这从来都不是关于权力
It was never about power.
你一直以来都是这样告诉自己的吗
Is that what you keep telling yourself?
我拯救了人类 奥德丽
I saved humanity, Audrey.
我的目标从出发第一日起就没变过
My goal has been the same from day one.
就是要保存生命 这也正是我所做的
That's to preserve life. And that's what I've done.
那么一切就都可以被原谅了
Well, everything's forgiven, then.
你想要我说什么
What do you want me to say?
我刻薄
I'm mean.
我无情
I'm ruthless.
我是禽兽 行啊 都是我
I'm a monster. Yeah, sure. All of it.
那又怎么样
And now what?
我的方法行不通
My way didn't work.
也许你的方法能行
Maybe yours will.
你怎么看 奥德丽
What do you think, Audrey?
我觉得她说的是真话
I think she's telling the truth.
提尔呢
Till?
我们似乎别无选择
I don't see what choice we have.
继续说
Keep talking.
火车头请回话
Come in, Engine.
-火车头请回话 -好极了
- Come in, Engine. - Yes.
梅兰妮
Melanie.
想不到是我吧
Believe it or not.
你没事吧 你在哪
You okay? Where are you?
我在三等厢 我没事
I'm in Third. I'm okay.
-在三等厢 -说来话长
- In Third? - Long story.
我们离费利蒙枢纽站还有多远
How far are we from the Fremont Junction?
费利蒙
Fremont?
大概一百公里 为什么这么问
About 100 kilometers. Why?
J表示结合链路
The "J" indicates a junction link.
安全阀都在这些控制面板里
Safeties are inside these panels.
只有最高级才有进入的权限
Access is top-level clearance only.
我会打开后车厢的安全阀
I'll release the downtrain safety,
但我们要有人在另一边 在敌人后方
but we need someone on the other side, behind enemy lines.
我可以上去 但我们需要更多的支援
I can get up there, but we're gonna need more help.
争吵 破坏行为
Brawls. Vandalism.
洗劫冷藏车厢
Looting in the refrigeration cars.
我整个早上都在解决麻烦
I've been putting out fires all morning.
你的新朋友
You know, your new friends,
有了活动空间时 还真是活跃
they're a lively bunch when they got room to roam.
我们获胜了 就会有和平
There will be peace when we win.
拜托 你就别鼓吹呐喊了 提尔
Please. Don't beat your drum in here, Till.
罗切 梅兰妮过了阵线边界
Roche. Melanie's crossed the lines.
她现在站在我们这边
She's on our side now.
和你 还有车尾人一起对抗头等厢吗
With you and the Tailies fighting against First?
你不相信我们的大业 好吧
You don't believe in the cause? Fine.
那就为正义而战 为你的家人而战
Then fight for what's right. Fight for your family.
为你的午餐肉而战
Fight for your -- your frickin' lunch meat!
他们把这也叫做午餐肉 太搞笑了
It's a travesty they call this lunch meat.
拜托 老大
Come on, boss.
现在只有一个办法了
There's only one way out of this now.
就连梅兰妮都能看出来
Even Melanie can see it.
就是我们
It's us.
意式脆饼 意式脆饼
Biscotti, biscotti, biscotti.
头等厢以及二等厢的女生们先生们
Ladies and gentlemen of First and Second Class,
我是管理部的主管
this is your Head of Hospitality speaking.
现在是中部时间下午1点32分
It's 1:32 P.M. Central Time.
这是一个令人不安的时期
This has been a troubling period,
但我们很高兴宣布
but we are pleased to announce
三等厢内已确保恢复和平
that peace in Third is now assured.
暴动势力已经同意投降
The mutinous faction has agreed to surrender,
所有的服务很快将会全面恢复
and all services will soon be restored in full.
我依旧代表已逝的威尔福德先生
As ever, on behalf of the late Mr. Wilford,
谢谢大家的耐心
we appreciate your patience.
-谢谢 -吉利斯老师
- Thank you. - Ms. Gillies.
谢谢你过来
thank you for coming.
真是松了口气
What a relief.
我想跟你讨论下
I j-just wanted to discuss tutoring for the...
-是的 -在跟后车的纷乱中 给孩子们辅导的事宜
- Yes. - ...for the boys during this -- this business with downtrain.
你确定我们还想这么做吗
Are you s-sure we still want to do this?
别担心 都在我们控制之中
Don't worry. We're on top of it.
除非你想要福爵一家掌管
Unless you want the Folgers to be in charge.
当然不想
To hell with that.
别担心
And don't worry.
加文和默里在经过辅导之后应该就没问题了
Gavin and Murray will be fine with a little bit of tutoring.
这可以让你打开安全阀
That will give you access to the safety release.
以及打开这列车上的每一道门
Also opens every door on this train.
我们成功的话 你和我之间的事可不算完
We pull this off, you and I, our business isn't finished.
哟哟哟 你们真是一对呢
Well, well, well, aren't you two the pair?
告诉我
Just tell me this.
有没有可能列车没法再接合
Is it possible the train won't reconnect?
如果时机掌握不对的话
If we blow the timing.
或者在分离期间出现损坏
Or if there's damage during the separation.
-就可能阻止重新连接 -然后会怎样
- It could prevent recoupling. - Then what?
然后列车后半部会冻住
Then the back half of the train will freeze.
前半部会挨饿
And the front half will starve.
好
Okay.
我就知道
Thought so.
就想听人大声说出来
Just wanted to hear someone say it out loud
这样我们就都知道这有多蠢了
so we all know how frickin' stupid this is.
我们走
Let's go.
打开
Open it up.
看看时间
Time.
当我释放这头
When I release this end...
我会有三分钟时间 明白
I'll have three minutes. Got it.
莱顿
Layton.
祝你好运
Good luck.
我们要进去了
We're coming in!
站住 搜他身
Stop. Frisk him.
真可笑
Ridiculous.
请过来 莱顿先生
Come forward, please, Mr. Layton.
请坐
Have a seat.
我们能快点说完吗
Can we get this over with, please?
好
Right.
那玩意在哪
Where's the thingy?
你在搞笑吧
You're kidding, right?
为了后代 莱顿先生
For posterity, Mr. Layton.
赢得战争还不够
It's not enough to win the war.
总有人得输
Someone has to lose.
盯着
Keep an eye on that.
时间
Time?
八分钟
Eight minutes.
到我左边 迈尔斯
To my left here, Miles.
听我指令
Wait for my command.
数到三后打开 二 一
Arm in three, two, one.
打开
Arm.
这是正式的投降书
This is the formal declaration of surrender.
你会向全车的人念出这段话
You'll be brought forward to say these words to the train.
在这签字
And sign here.
大家站过来
Gather 'round, everyone.
包括你 罗切
You too, Roche.
-再拍一张 -够了
- Just one more. - Alright, enough with this!
人们很焦虑 我们得
People are anxious. We got to get --
我们得快点
We got to get on with this.
好 好 如你所愿 起来
Alright. Alright. As you wish. Up.
铐住他
Handcuff him.
指挥官
Commander.
我们要留下来
We're staying here.
等莱顿先生发表声明后
When Mr. Layton's announcement goes out,
我们会和军队回去 接受三等厢的投降
we'll go back with the troops and accept Third's surrender.
务必让公民
It's important that the citizens
亲眼看到新权力结构
see the new power structure in the flesh.
不再有欺诈
No more...fakery.
不再有演戏
No more theater.
如你所愿
As you wish.
你们跟我来
You men, come with me.
其余的人留下
The rest of you, stay here.
我们对你感激不尽 莱顿先生
We owe you a debt of gratitude, Mr. Layton.
你移除了我们的眼罩
You removed our blinders.
你从烂泥里爬出来
You...crawled up out of the slime
带来了真相
and brought the truth with you.
不客气
You're welcome.
上啊 各位 告诉他你们的感受
Go ahead, boys! Tell him how you feel!
好了 好了
Alright, boys. Alright.
够了 够了
Enough, enough, enough.
格雷 你想在我被锁住的时候
Grey, you want to take your shot at me
揍我吗
while they got me chained?
我的要留着呢
Oh, I'm saving mine.
我揍你的时候 你会感受到的
When it lands, you'll know it.
解开他的手铐
Uncuff him.
你怎么也叛变 罗切
Not you too, Roche.
快解开
Cuffs. Quickly.
-解开 -好
- Get them off. - Alright.
你知道这里一颗子弹能造成多大危害吗
Do you know how much damage a bullet can do down here?
我指望你的脑壳能减慢它的速度
I'm counting on your brain pan to slow it down.
你们俩 趴下
You two, on the floor.
现在
Now.
什么情况
What was that?
就是现在了
This is it.
好了 加速 制造分离
Alright, throttle up. Create separation.
让莱顿完成他的任务
And let Layton do his thing.
那是农业和家禽的车厢
That's agriculture, poultry.
我们不能没有它们
We can't live without that.
老天
Jesus.
三等厢不是目标
Third's not the target.
扶他起来
Get him up!
安德烈·莱顿 你被判犯有煽动叛乱罪
Andre Layton, you've been found guilty of sedition.
我在此判决你立即执行死刑
I hereby sentence you to immediate execution.
让开 让开 让开
Move, move, move! Move!
-莱拉 莱拉 -小莱 小莱
- Lilah! Lilah! - LJ! LJ! LJ!
够了 够了
Hey, hey, hey, hey, okay, enough, enough.
你们快去前车
You guys gotta get uptrain now! Go!
搞什么 莱顿 大力士成中国人了
What the hell, Layton? Strong Boy's gone Chinese.
-我们要去前线 -没空解释了
- We're looking for the front. - There's no time to explain, alright?
把司闸员扶起来 他现在是我们的人了
Grab the Brakeman. He is one of us now.
上车 到前车去 快
Get in the car! Get uptrain! Go! Go!
你在哪 莱顿
Where are you, Layton?
快啊 莱顿 拜托
Any time, Layton! Come on!
情况不太妙
Something bad's happening.
你来了
You're here!
快 快
Come on! Come on!
快 我们得离开
Hey, come on. We got to get out of here.
-钥匙在哪 -什么钥匙
- Where are the keys? - What keys?
-我们有时间 -他有钥匙吗
- We got time. - D-D-Does he have keys?
他 钥匙在哪
Does he have -- Where are the keys?!
等等
Wait.
钥匙
Keys.
不 不 不 不 不 不
No, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no.
我们找到别的办法 我们总是能找到
We find another way. We always do.
-钥匙在哪 -怎么了 孩子
- Where are the keys? - What is it, son?
你怎么一直看你的表
Why do you keep looking at your watch?
没时间了
There's no time.
怎么了
What's going on?
抱歉
I'm sorry.
桑迪 我爱你 兄弟
Santi, I love you, brother.
-我也爱你 -没时间了
- Love you, too, man. - There's no time.
-抱歉什么 -没时间了
- Sorry for what? - There's no time.
但你就在这儿
But you're right here.
我爱你 桑迪
I love you, Santi.
怎么了
What's wrong?
等等 怎么回事
Wait, what's happening?
-抱歉 -你去哪
- I am sorry. - Where are you going?
-抱歉 -莱顿
- I am sorry. - Layton.
抱歉
I'm sorry.
你去哪
Where are you going, man?!
-莱顿 -抱歉
- Layton? - I'm sorry.
等等 你去哪
Hold on! Where you going?!
-莱顿 -你去哪
- Layton. - Where are you going?!
莱顿
Layton!
别走
Don't walk away!
关掉
Go now!
按住 按住 保持稳定
Get ahold of that. Get ahold of that. Keep it steady.
我去关掉 然后你放缓速度
I'll switch them off, then you slow us down.
好
Okay.
准备换轨道
Ready to switch tracks.
革命万岁
Viva la revolucion.
万岁 兄弟
Viva, brother.
我女儿 我女儿
My daughter! My daughter!
大家 请留在后面
Everyone -- Everyone, please, just stay in the back.
留在后面
Stay in the back.
罗伯特
Robert.
小莱孤身一人
LJ's all alone.
莱拉
Lilah.
我的莱拉
My Lilah.
降速 迈尔斯 还要再降速
Reduce speed, Miles. Take off even more.
好样的
Good job.
有我在
I gotcha.
我们做到了
We did it.
好样的 工程师
Good job, Engineer.
你早知道我得丢下他们
You knew I'd have to cut them.
我知道那会是你的选择
I knew the choice would be yours.
这是我们必须承受的
It's what we live with.
我们存在的每一秒
Every second of our existence.
列车归你了 莱顿
You have the train, Layton.